Guide to the Andrew Forest Muir papers MS 017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VI: Original treasury notes and manuscripts, 1763-1908, 252377
  - Subseries B: Manuscripts, 1763-1908, 252418
    - Military, 252435
      - Oath of Office, blank, n.d., 252436 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Legal docket, C.B. Sabin, Justice of the Peace, Harris County, Texas, 1850-1857 (unbound), 252434 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Trade, 252422
      - Massachusetts export permit for Ichabod Nichols, 22 July 1780, 252433 (Box 80, Folder 17)
      - Invoice [City of] New Orleans to pay Felix Arnaud, 1816, 252432 (Box 80, Folder 18)
      - Constitution of Portland City Co., Matagorda, Republic of Texas, 252431 (Box 80, Folder 19)
      - Schmidt & Ziegler grocer's receipt, New Orleans, 1872, 252430 (Box 80, Folder 20)
      - Shipping receipt, Philadelphia & Southern Mail Steamship Co., 1872, 252429 (Box 80, Folder 21)
      - Shipping receipt, Port of New York, 1872, 252428 (Box 80, Folder 22)
      - Shipping receipt, Morgan Lines U.S. Mail Steamers – New Orleans and Texas, 1872, 252427 (Box 80, Folder 23)
      - Lumber receipt, H.J. Huck & Co., Cuero, TX, 1895, 252426 (Box 80, Folder 24)
      - Promise to pay $114 from W.J. Gorman, Goliad, TX, 1864, 252425 (Box 80, Folder 25)
      - Lumber yard advertisement, Pearl River, NY, ca. 1860, 252424 (Box 80, Folder 26)
      - Washington County Canal lottery ticket #3180, n.d., 252423 (Box 80, Folder 27)
    - Land, 252419
      - Land in City of Austin, agreement between William Penney and J.L. Ward, May 23, 1840, 252421 (Box 80, Folder 28)
      - Land survey inquiry to San Antonio de Bexar, 1851, 252420 (Box 80, Folder 29)
  - Railroad: Galveston, Houston and Henderson Railroad Co., correspondence from Office #49 in New York City, 1857, 252417 (Box 80, Folder 30)
  - Railroad: Southern Trans-Continental Railroad / Memphis, El Paso and Pacific Railroad Company bond, 1868, 252416 (Box 80, Folder 31)
  - Railroad: Houston and Texas Central Railroad Company, correspondence from Superintendent's Office, Corsicana, TX, 1877, 252415 (Box 80, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 252401
    - Correspondence and affidavits: John F. Seymour to Horatio S.D. ___, March 28, 1853; R. Haldam to Ruth ---, Sept. 25, 1898; R. King Cutler, US Senator-elect of Louisiana to Hon. H.B. Anthony, US Senator, March 6, 1865; C.R. Wade to Nellie ___, Jan. 18, 1862; T. Pearce to ___, written in Latin, Oct. 2, 1739; affidavit of Jacob Jacobs of London, May 4, 1790, 252414 (Box 80, Folder 33)
    - Lydia Foster to "Dear Uncle", Jan. 21, 1853, 252413 (Box 80, Folder 34)
    - From S.W. Preston, aboard U.S. steamship frigate "Wabash", Nov. 15, 1861, 252412 (Box 80, Folder 35)
    - H.S. Bennett to "son Emmett Bennett, from Paris, TX, Dec. 28, 1871, 252411 (Box 80, Folder 36)
    - M.C. Hamilton, from Senate Chamber, Washington DC., March 1, 1871, 252410 (Box 80, Folder 37)
    - Elizabeth Hallmark to Thomas Ewing, Feb. 11, 1876, 252409 (Box 80, Folder 38)
    - Robert Woodward Barnwell Elliott to "My dear lady", Philadelphia, Nov. 28, 1881, 252408 (Box 80, Folder 39)
    - W.H. Hare to Robert Woodward Barnwell Elliott, Springfield Dakota, May 1, 1882, 252407 (Box 80, Folder 40)
    - Aunt Emma to Mary, Sept. 4, 1980, 252406 (Box 80, Folder 41)
    - To "My dear Emma", Nov. 9, 1890, 252405 (Box 80, Folder 42)
    - From John B. Phillips, Matagorda, TX, 1892 and 1893, 252404 (Box 80, Folder 43)
    - R. Mills to Rev. Richard Kaines, Corsicana, TX, Nov. 7, 1895, 252403 (Box 80, Folder 44)
    - George H. Kinsolving to "My Dear Sir", Austin, TX, March 3, 1908, 252402 (Box 80, Folder 45)
  - Ballad "The Overland Rangers" written for Thomas J. Ewing, 1865, 252400 (Box 80, Folder 46)
  - Warrant for the arrest of William Douglas, Loudon County (Virginia?), June 11, 1763, 252399 (Box 80, Folder 47)
  - Fanny Ewing calling cards, n.d., 252398 (Box 80, Folder 48)
  - Funeral notices: Ewing & Hermann families, Houston, 1860s-1870s, 252397 (Box 80, Folder 49)
  - Death certificate of child of W.H. Schwartz, Houston, May 19, 1894, 252396 (Box 80, Folder 50)
  - Signature of Alex Gregg, Bishop of Texas, Sewanne, TN, Sept. 26, 1887, 252395 (Box 80, Folder 51)
  - Autographs and seals (Samuel _allows, Bishop of the Reformed Episcopal Church, Chicago 1879; Seal of Samuel Horsley, Bishop of St. Asaph, 1802; Seal of John Moore, Archbishop of Canterbury, 1783; autographs of Zane Grey, Helen Keller, Dan Moody, Will Rogers, Franklin D. Roosevelt), 252394 (Box 80, Folder 52)
  - Photographs and other images: Gen. Benj. McCullough, C.S.A., n.d.; Interior of St. Paul's Church, Oakland, CA, Easter 1874, with Chas. M. Turner, Rector, at altar; Stereoview of Grace Cathedral, San Fransisco, Easter Sunday, n.d.; Robert Burton Hall, n.d.; Alexander Charles Garrett, n.d.; DeWitt Clinton Harris, n.d.; Dr. Newman, Cape Town, n.d., 252393 (Box 80, Folder 53)
  - Judiciary (1868) & Executive Committee (n.d.) reports (published) Texas, 252392 (Box 80, Folder 54)
  - Booklet: A Practical Inquiry into New Testament Doctrine…", by Eld. J.B. Link, published by Office of Texas Baptist Herald, Houston, 1878, 252391 (Box 80, Folder 55)
  - Booklet: "The Human Nature of Jesus" by J.D. Shaw, published in Waco, TX, 1890, 252390 (Box 80, Folder 56)
  - Booklet: "The Bible: What is it?", published Waco, TX, 1891, 252389 (Box 80, Folder 57)
  - Engraving of Ricord's Seminary at Geneva, Ontario County, NY, n.d., 252388 (Box 80, Folder 58)
  - Broadsides and imprints: Broadside of The Children's American Church Missionary Society (New York), undated; title page and preface of Sermons on Important Subjects by the Late Reverend and Pious Samuel Davies, A.M., Sometime President of the College in New Jersey, Vol. 1, 1794, with birth records of the Bradley family (1806-1825); Title page to Short Studies on Great Subjects, by James Anthony Fronde., 252387 (Box 80, Folder 59)
  - Pencil and ink sketch of AFM as a young man, 12"x18", n.d., 252386 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - Reproduction of original oil painting by Tom Lea entitled "Ranger Escort West of the Pecos", 15"x18", n.d., 252385 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - Reproductions (3) of pen and ink study of J. Frank Dobie by Tom Lea, 15"x18", n.d., 252384 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - Photograph of Walter Prescott Webb by Dan Hardy, printed above quote from Houston Post, and inscribed to AFM: "To Andrew Forest Muir, historian extraoridnaire, Walter Prescott Webb", n.d., 252383 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - Chalk sketch of Alex James Borge by Kurt Hans Winkler in Honolulu, 1962, 252382 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - Photograph of William Joseph Muir, elder brother of AFM, 16"X18", n.d., 252381 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - Photographs of Walter Prescott Webb by Dan Hardy (1 8"x10") and J. Frank Dobie on his 70th birthday (1 8"x10"), 252380 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - "Revised map of Jefferson County, TX showing land surveys, railroads and water ways, up to date 1898", 252379 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
  - Color rendering of The Alamo, by C.A. Walker, June 6, 1888, 252378 (Drawer #33, Folder -)
- Series VII: Microfilm, 1800s, 252368
  - National Archives:, 252373
    - Union Land Company (1 reel), 252376 (Box 81, Folder -)
    - Hoyt vs. Hammeken (1 reel), 252375 (Box 81, Folder 30)
    - Hammeken vs. Mexico (1 reel), 252374 (Box 81, Folder -)
  - Elizabeth Stryker Ricord & Frederick William Ricord papers, original mss in possession of family, Newark, NJ as of 1969 (1 reel), 252372 (Box 81, Folder -)
  - Macomb Family letters 1807-1834, 1896; Thomas Worthington mss collection. Likely copy from Ohio Historical Society. (1 reel), 252371 (Box 81, Folder -)
  - Clopper family papers, original mss in possession of Dr. Edward Nicholas Clopper, Cincinatti, OH as of 1969. (1 reel), 252370 (Box 81, Folder -)
  - Spanish documents: Informe Que el Socio Gerente Da a Los Senores Accionistas de la Compania del Camino del Fierro de Tacubaya. Jorge Luis Hammeken, Mexico, 1860 (unreeled film), 252369 (Box 81, Folder -)
- Series VIII: Muir diaries and ledgers, 1911-1950, 252355
  - Record of Social Security Savings, 1937, 252367 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Personal diary, 1934; 252366 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Personal diary, 1937; 252365 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Personal diary, 1938; 252364 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Ledger with Houston national Bank checking account information, 1936-1941, 252363 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Cash book recording expenses, 1942-1943, 252362 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Postcards from H.H. Kellogg to Muir, 1949-1950, 252361 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - War ration book, 1942-1944 (3), 252360 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Postcard from Harris County War & Price Rationing Board, 1944, 252359 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Muir regarding application for auto parts, Aug. 25, 1943, 252358 (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - War Price & Ration Board certificates for auto parts, Sept. 20, 1943 (2), 252357 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Sunday School Secretary's Record, Clemen's Memorial Church of Houston, 1911, ownership listed as Joseph Bailey Muir, Superintendant, 252356 (Box 82, Folder 12)